本字幕由网络爱好者联盟原创翻译
欢迎加入我们 www.ZiMuZu.pub
在保留译者名单的前提下任何人不需要经得我们的同意
可用本字幕做任何用途因此所产生的后果由您自行承担
■
翻译：为小李子拔刀  低调付付
翻译：colorofmyblood  rania.  uhello
■
校对与后期：夏棒棒  大红
片头推广合作洽谈：请联系普罗米修斯邮箱 PLMXS2016@GmaiL.com
■
理查德  情况很不妙
It doesn't look good, Richard.
实际上  坦白说  很糟糕
In fact, to be quite frank, it looks pretty bad.
与其拐弯抹角
Rather than beat around the bush,
我会直接跟你说出来
I'm just gonna come right out and say it.
理查德  你得了四期肺癌
Richard, you have stage four lung cancer.
肺癌临床上共四期  第四期即为晚期
你上背部感觉到的疼痛
The pain you've been experiencing in your upper back
实际上  是由你肺里的
is actually the result of malignant tumors
恶性肿瘤造成的
within your lungs,
很遗憾  这情况已经挺久了
which it sadly appears you have for some time.
即使我们再早点发现
As we're catching this late in the game,
你的癌细胞还是会机会扩散
your cancer has also had the opportunity to spread
尤其会往你的脊椎  和肾上腺转移
specifically to your spine, and adrenals.
你应该通知学校
You wanna put in notice with the college.
并尽快告诉维罗妮卡  还有你女儿
You should notify Veronica and your daughter
治疗立即就要开始
as soon as possible as treatment will begin immediately.
我还有多长时间
How long are we talking?
积极治疗的话  一年
With treatment, a year,
如果足够幸运的话  或许一年半
a year and a half, if you're lucky.
不治疗呢
And without?
大概半年
Probably six months.
我很抱歉  理查德
I am so sorry, Richard.
教授
草
Fuck.
这个季度极其棒
So let's make this a fantastic quarter.
我们一直缺的那块资金  现在补上了
We get that extra little bit of funding that we so desperately need.
还有问题吗
Uh, any questions?
操你大爷
Fuck.
额  就这样  散会
What...? Uhm... Okay.
干
Fuck.
操妈逼上帝
Jesus fucking Jesus.
耶稣  上帝  干
Jesus. God. Fuck.
草泥马狗杂种
Fucking bastard!
干你妹  耶稣
Fuck! Jesus!
去死吧
Fuck it, huh?
去你妈的上帝
Fucking God!
操你妈逼
Fuck you!
你妈的  为什么
Fuck you.
该死
Fuck.
第一章
我有些话想说
无神论者会做祷告吗
Shall the atheist say grace then?
闭嘴  理查德
Shut up, Richard.
当然  亲爱的
Of course, my dear.
我倒是有些话想说
I actually have something I wanna say.
说吧  孩子  想说什么
Go ahead, kid. What do you got?
我想让你们知道  我是同性恋
I wanted you to know that I'm gay.
你在开什么玩笑
What on Earth?
我的老天爷
Jesus Christ.
奥莉维亚  我以为是什么很糟的事呢
Olivia, I thought it was something bad.
不  你可不是同性恋  奥莉
No, you're not, Olive.
你说我不是  什么意思
What do you mean I'm not?
你不是同性恋  我是说  你不是拉拉
You're not gay. I mean, you're not a lesbian.
不  我是
Yeah, I am.
不  我知道自己的性取向
Yeah. No, I think I'd know my own sexual preference.
呃  这只是人生中一个阶段
Uh, it's just a phase.
我  个人认为  觉得这太棒了
I, for one, think it's fantastic.
别安慰她
Don't placate her.
我不是在安慰我女儿
I'm not placating my daughter.
你怎么敢就这样否定我
How dare you deny me like this.
我没有反对你  宝贝
I'm not denying you, sweetheart.
我只是在否定以这种方式引起我们的注意
I'm just denying your call for attention
不管你认为这是什么   就这样
or whatever else this is. That's all.
我比你自己更了解你  奥莉
I know you, Olive, better than you know yourself.
不  妈妈  你一丁点都不了解我
No, mother. You know no shit about me.
奥莉维亚  快回来  回来
Olivia, please come back, sweetheart. Olivia.
让她去吧
Let her go.
你教育子女的方式
Your finesse of parenting...
总是能惊到我
has always amazed me.
我也有话想说
I also have something I'd like to say.
我都等不及了
I can't wait.
我出轨了
I'm having an affair.
我出轨了  我想你应该知道
I'm having an affair and I thought you should know.
你为什么认为我应该知道
And why did you think I should know?
因为  对方是亨利
Because it's with Henry.
哪个亨利
Henry who?
亨利·怀特
Henry Wright.
-亨利·怀特  -对
- Henry Wright? - Uh-hmm.
我的老板吗
My boss?
不  不行  不可能
No, no, no, no.
维罗妮卡  这太恶心了
Veronica. That's real revolting.
你疯了吗  拜托
Are you out of your mind? Come on.
至少出轨的对象有点品位吧
At least have a little bit of taste in your infidelity.
这是你的事  但我干过泳池救生员
It's up to you, but I'd fucked a pool boy myself
还是水管工  我忘了
or a plumber.
然后我就软了
Then had some fucking nutless sack.
我向你保证一点都不空虚
I assure you it's not empty.
什么
What?
因为天佑亨利有一个额外的睾丸
Henry has been blessed with a spare testicle.
天佑亨利有一个额外的睾丸
Henry was blessed with a spare testicle?
你确定这不是囊肿  或肿瘤吗
Are you sure it's not a cyst or a cancerous growth?
你还在乎吗
Do you even care?
关于他的三个卵蛋吗
About his third nut?
不  不  我不在乎
No. No, I don't.
在我看来  房地产
As far as I'm concerned, that real estate's
早就失去了投资价值
lost its value long ago.
你真是个混蛋
You're such an ass.
我承认
Self-admitted.
所以为我们神圣的婚姻干杯吧
So let us drink to our holy matrimony.
你自己喝吧
Drink by yourself.
不错的建议
Much better idea.
呃  你想告诉我们什么
Ugh. What was it you wanted to tell us?
我 我担心牛排煮太久了
I was, uh, afraid I overcooked the steaks.
真是个混球
Such an asshole.
不  但她根本不是这么说的
No, but that's not what she's saying at all.
她是在为整个女权运动奠定基础
She's laying the groundwork for the whole feminist movement.
继续
Go on.
就像一百年前那样
Like a hundred years in advance and...
那是什么
What was that?
噢
Oh.
你不做些什么吗
Aren't you gonna do anything?
比如说
Like what?
我不清楚  打电话什么的
I don't know. Call someone.
你和它是朋友吗
Were you friends with it?
你认识它吗  比如  名字
Did you know it personally, by, like, by name?
这就是只该死的鸟
It's a fucking bird.
我不知道要给谁打电话
I don't know who to call.
-我能继续吗  -不  不行
- Can I continue? - No, you may not.
噢  谁的手机响了  是你的吗
Oh, whose phone is it? Is that your phone?
该死
Shit.
好了  是这位同学
There we go. Here she is.
抱歉
Sorry.
是我的  对不起
Mine. Sorry.
我以为是振动模式  但是
Um, I thought it was on vibrate but it's...
不  不  没事
No, no, no, please,
接电话  站起来接电话
take your call. Stand up and take your call.
来吧  别害羞
Please. Don't be shy.
站起来接电话
Stand up and take your call.
哪位
Hello.
我回头再打给你  我正在上课
I'm gonna call you back actually because I'm in class.
不  真正在上课
No, as in I'm in class.
现在  我正站着
Right now. I'm standing up.
我知道很奇怪  好吧
I know it's weird. Okay.
再见  再见  再见
Goodbye. Bye. Bye.
真迷人
Fascinating.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
哦  不必如此
Oh, don't be.
好了
Okay.
从现在开始
From here on out,
我们会和以往非常  非常不同
we're gonna do things very, very differently.
在座的各位  要是对此不感兴趣
So for those of you who are not even remotely interested
现在就可以直接离开了
in being here, please leave.
只要走出门
Just simply walk out the door
结课必定能得到一个C
and you'll receive an automatic C.
我没有多少时间可以浪费
I no longer have time to be wasted
我也不打算浪费你们的时间
nor do I intend on wasting yours.
所以对于那些
So for those of you who receive grades of,
比如说  只能拿C  或是更糟的
say, a C or worse,
积极主动点
let's just be proactive.
带上东西  走吧
Pack up your shit. And vamos now.
怎么样
Hmm?
不错  继续
Good. Here we go.
如果你们有人打算学习商业
If any of you have any intentions of studying business,
现在就出去吧
get the fuck out now.
我不会再说第二遍
I'm not gonna say it again.
如果你低头  发现自己穿着运动裤
If you look down and you happen to find yourself in sweatpants
或者是带腰绳的裤子之类的
or rather pants with the drawstring or something,
请出去
just please leave.
最重要的一点
Most important of all,
如果你从来没有为自己内心的欢愉读过书
if you've never read a book for our own internal pleasure...
你不属于这里  出去吧
you don't belong here. Get out.
如果你们有人发现自己
If any of you find yourself
属于上述任何一类
falling into any of these categories.
我保证  你不会拿到比C更高分数
I assure you, you will not do better than a C.
继续
Here we go.
还有政府部门工作人员和从政者
The government workers and the politicians included.
运动裤可不仅仅是开玩笑
The, uh, sweatpants comment is not a joke.
我生病了  感冒
I'm sick. I have a cold.
好了  现在  那些有兴趣
Right. Now, for those of you who are interested in
学习更伟大思想的人  今天是时候了
learning from greater minds, and there are today,
你们负责读一本书
you're in charge of reading one book
这个季度只有一本书
and one book only to this quarter.
这样做之后  你就可以站在这里
After doing so, you will then stand up here
开设你自己的课了
and you will run a class of your own.
干得漂亮  现在是饮水机边的国王和皇后
Excellent. There go the kings and queens of the water cooler,
明天就是给大公司卖命的工作狂
corporate whores of tomorrow.
也许是C  也许不是
C. Maybe not.
然后你可以站在这里  劝说你的同龄人
And then you will stand up here and you'll persuade your peers
这项工作有多重要
of the work's importance.
为此  你将得到一个B
For that, you'll receive a B.
如果你能教我们一些新东西  就能得到A
If you teach us something new, you receive an A.
还有问题吗
Any questions?
额
Um...
啊哈  对了  还有一件事
Ah-ha. Yes. One more thing.
不能宣扬女权主义或同性恋
No feminist or queer propaganda.
我现在最不需要关心的事情
The plight of unkempt women is truly the last thing
就是不注重仪表的女人们的困境
I would like to think about right now.
我觉得你不能这么规定
I don't think you can do that.
我已经做了规定
I just did.
现在  我将开启随心所欲
And now, I shall embark on an emotional...
狂欢的72小时
bender for 72 hours.
最可能的  是我一个人喝酒
Most likely, I'll be drinking alone
我觉得那还行
and I'm all right with that.
因此  结果就是  课程取消
So as a result, class is cancelled.
结束
That's it.
下课
Class dismissed.
哦  对了  顺便问一句  你们有人卖大麻
Oh, yeah, by the way, if any of you sell marijuana
或者认识卖大麻的人
or you know anyone who does,
能在办公时间过来找我一下吗
would you please visit me during office hours?
谢了  拜拜
Thanks. Bye.
什么鬼
What the fuck?
下个季度我要开始学术休假
I need to go on sabbatical next quarter.
是美国大学教师发展的一种重要制度形式  每隔一定年限
在全薪或减薪的情况下  研究者外出休整一年或稍短的时间
我会  不  我不会准你学术休假
I would... No, I can't give you a sabbatical,
那要一年呢
it takes a year.
准备学术休假的申请要一年的时间
A year to get that kind of thing done.
你得做点什么来加快速度
You're gonna have to do something to speed it up.
不  我不能
No, I can't.
你要学术休假干什么
What do you want to go on a sabbatical for?
我想写出下一部美国最精彩的小说
I would like to write the next great American novel.
哦  是吗
Oh, yeah?
或短篇  取决于长度
Or novela,depending on the length.
关于什么
What's it about?
关于孤儿养兔子的故事
It's gonna be about an orphan who raises rabbits or bunnies around there.
叫什么名字
And what's it called?
现在  暂定的题目是  寻找兔兔乐
Right now, the tentative title is Bunny Fun Found
因为她的名字叫兔兔   奇怪的是
because her name is Bunny and oddly enough,
-她玩得很开心  -真是扯淡
- she was having fun... - You're full of shit.
你满嘴跑火车  是在骗我
You're full of shit. You're having me on.
-皮特  我得了癌症  -什么
- I have cancer, Peter. - What?
我得了癌症  而且情况很不妙
I have cancer and it doesn't get look good.
天啊  理查德
Jesus Christ, Richard.
我不想死在这里
I don't want to die here.
我不想死在像这样的地方
I don't wanna die here like this.
求你让我出去  就让我孤独的死去
Please get me out. Just let me die alone.
让我平静地死去
Let me die in peace.
理查德
Oh, Richard.
不要在桌子上拉手
No hands above the table.
好吧
Okay.
是什么癌症
What kind of cancer is it?
是肺癌
It's, uh, it's lung cancer.
可你从不抽烟
You don't smoke.
不  我现在可以抽了
No. I can now.
听着  每个人都有可能这样
Listen, this is what happens to everybody.
这就是我们所有人不容逃避的现实
It's what happens to all of us.
我是说  你也可能长满了这鬼东西
I mean, you could be ridden with the same damn thing.
你为什么要对我说这些
Why would you say something like that to me, huh?
不  我只是在表达论点  很抱歉
No, no. I'm making a point. I'm sorry.
说出来意思就不太对了
It came out wrong.
-我很抱歉  真对不住  -没关系
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - That's allright.
酒来了
There you go.
我真讨厌这些女人气的杯子
I really hate these effeminate glasses.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我会把药柜装满
I'm gonna fill my medicine cabinet.
还有
And...
我要直接挺过去
I'm gonna ride this thing out.
等等  你不接受治疗吗
Wait, you're not gonna get treatments?
不
No.
-你欠我的  皮特  -是啊
- You owe me, Peter. - Uh, yes.
对  是的  当然
Yes. Yes, of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
你现在可以松开我的手
You can let go of my hands now
然后我们就能一块喝酒了
and then we can have a drink maybe.
-好  -谢了
- Yeah. - Thank you.
敬最后这几个月的时间
So to the months end.
为了你的健康
To your health.
不要需要开玩笑
There's no need to be facetious.
我不是故意开玩笑的
I didn't mean to be facetious.
还有你那碎嘴  别出去跟人乱讲
And don't go blabbering your little wet mouth about this.
-不  不会的  -我生病和别人没关系
- No, no. - This is no one's business.
-只是我的事  -当然了
- but my own. - Of course.
我认为你的艺术作品是出色的  令人惊叹的
I think your art is brilliant, stunning,
而且非常值得投资
and a wonderful investment.
实际上
In fact...
你可以把校园弄弄吗  雕塑啥的
could you do the whole campus?
-当然凭你的天赋  -去佛罗里达大学吗
- Certainly with your talent... - To the College of Florida?
那是我的职责
That's my responsibility.
你不用担心
You don't need to worry about that.
为你最近的出轨喝一杯
To your latest infidelity.
还有你那光荣的绿帽子
And your honorable cuckolding.
这是什么
Ooh, what's that?
这是一颗长型白色药片
It's a white oblong pill.
你从哪儿弄来的
Where did you get it?
我们现在是有钱的中年人了
We're well-to-do middle-aged wasps.
想要什么药都能拿到处方  亲爱的
We can get prescriptions for anything we want, darling.
好吧
Okay.
你要是表现得好
If you behave yourself...
我就再给你个蓝色三角的
I'll give you a blue triangular one next.
听说你很喜欢
I heard you're quite fond of them.
说正事
Onto serious matters.
-说吧  -你心里知道
- Go for it. - And you know at heart,
我一点都不在乎你和亨利的事
I don't give a damn about you and Henry.
你想做什么就做什么  但你必须明白
You do whatever you please. But you have to realize
从现在开始  我也会过得无拘无束
that from here on out, I'll be living just as freely.
在我们悲剧的婚姻中
I've played a rather quiet role in
我一直都是默不作声的那个
the tragedy that is our marriage.
还有
and...
老实说  我受够了
quite frankly, I'm done.
是时候发泄一下  内心最原始的欲望了
It's time that we lived a bit closer to the... primal truth of it all.
所以从现在开始  我俩想干谁就干谁
So from this point on, let us fuck who we wanna fuck.
想吃什么就吃什么
Let us ingest what we wanna ingest.
总之  只要高兴  想做什么做什么
And all in all, just do whatever the hell we damn well please.
好啊  喝一杯
Here, here.
只有一个要求
One request,
我们都谨慎一点
that we do so discretely.
尽量不要伤害到
Let us at least attempt to keep the parental damage
我们可爱的拉拉女儿
to our sweet lesbian love child to a minimum.
我打从心底里同意
I wholeheartedly agree.
很好  问题解决了
Wonderful. And the matter is settled.
理查德
Richard?
怎么了  亲爱的
Yes, dear?
我能问一下你那家伙还能用吗
Dare I ask if your equipment still works?
我也不知道
I don't know.
很可惜  它已经休眠很多年了
I mean, sadly, it's laid dormant for years.
如果不能用了  刚好再搞个处方药治治
But if it doesn't, it's just one more prescription to fill.
这个  敬我们的新生活
Here's to, uh, our new lives.
还有你重获自由
And your new freedoms.
现在  把奖励我的蓝色药丸给我吧
Now, hand over a blue one I've behaved myself admirably.
他有点像  呃
He was like this, um...
一个爱上了自己表妹的17世纪的诗人
17th century poet who fell in love with his cousin and...
-爱上了自己的表妹  -我草
- ...fell in love with his cousin? - Oh, shit.
你真是个混蛋
You're such an asshole.
-怎么了  -我爸妈在家
- What? - My parents are home.
没关系的
Hey. It's okay.
你能答应我  别评价吗
Can you promise not to judge me?
不用担心  真的
Don't worry, seriously.
它坏掉了
It's broken. Hmm.
我是说  整个都坏掉了
I mean, the whole thing is broken.
真是
That's .
奥莉维亚  快看  亲爱的
Oh, Olivia. Look, dear.
-奥莉维亚和她朋友来了  -这怎么了
- It's Olivia andhis company. - What's going on?
你妈妈把灯弄坏了
Uh, your mom broke the lamp.
你俩还好吗
Are you all right?
当然了  亲爱的  怎么会不好呢
Yes, darling. Of course, why wouldn't we be?
因为你俩看上去喝多了  要不就是嗑药了
Because you seem like you're drunk or on drugs.
我们其实两样都来了点
Admittedly, we are on a bit of both.
但别让这个影响你的决定
But don't let that influence your decisions.
哦  别听他瞎说
Oh, don't listen to him.
只是些处方药  我是奥莉维亚的妈妈维罗妮卡
They're just prescriptions. I'm Veronica, Olivia's mother.
嗨  我是泰勒
Hi, I'm Taylor.
很高兴见到你
Oh, nice to meet you...
不好意思
Excuse me.
小心  亲爱的  别太激动
Careful, dear. Let's not exert yourself.
那她一定就是
So is this... is she...
妈妈  泰勒就是泰勒
Taylor is Taylor, mother.
是啊  当然是了
Yes, yes, of course, you are.
顺便说一下  我是理查德
And by the way, I'm Richard.
-你要喝点吗  -当然  快来
- Would you like a drink? - Yes, please, come.
-一起来喝一杯  -等一下  不行
- Join us for a drink. - No, hang on. No.
你们这样太吓人了  我们走了
You're being very creepy. We're going.
-吓人吗  -没错
- Creepy? - Yes.
我们只是找点乐子
We're just having fun.
走了
Come on.
嘿  很高兴见到你
Hey, well, it was very nice meeting you.
再见  很高兴认识你
Bye. Nice to meet you.
还不错啊
That was pleasant.
你觉得她俩怎么样
So how do you think that went?
1到10分的话
On a scale of one to ten,
我打4分
I'd say a four.
同意
Agreed.
我只是对自己有点失望
I'm only mildly disappointed in myself.
我感到有些羞愧
I feel ashamed. Yeah.
我们这是怎么了  理查德
What happened to us, Richard?
我们到底怎么了
What happened to us?
生活
Life.
你知道吗  就算我能回到过去
You know, if I could go back in time,
我也不知道应该挽回些什么
I don't even know what it is I'm supposed to fix.
我能很容易想到许多事
Oh, I could readily think of many things.
我没问你
I didn't ask you.
没错
True.
你要把我们所有的结婚礼物都弄坏了
You're gonna break all our wedding presents.
有没有注意到它们都很空洞
Did you ever notice that they're all hollow?
这是什么意思
Ah, what does that mean?
不用在意了
It doesn't matter.
理查德
Richard?
怎么了  亲爱的
Yes, dear?
谢谢你帮我
Thank you for helping me.
这还用谢
Of course.
你吐的时候帮你拢住头发
Holding your hair back has
是我这辈子的荣幸之一
always been one of my life's great honors.
我认真的
I'm serious.
从某种意义上说  我也是认真的
In ways, so am I.
你觉得奥莉维亚恨我吗
Do you think Olivia hates me?
恨
Yes.
但她也没有错
But she's supposed to.
我不是个坏人
I'm not a bad person.
我知道  维罗妮卡
I know you're not, Veronica.
没有人说你是个坏人
No one ever said you were.
第二章
操就要操对了
你们是相对来说比较有吸引力的孩子
Well, you are a... relatively attractive group of kids.
我意思是  我几乎看不到有软弱的人
I mean, I see a few weak chins here and there.
但是  我想这很可能是
But, uh, I think that's probably just
因为新英格兰的良好教育
due to some fine New England breeding. Hmm?
美丽的母亲  有钱的父亲
Beautiful mother, rich father,
寒冷的冬天  类似这些
cold winter, that kind of thing.
你抽烟吗
Do you smoke?
不
No.
你看着像抽烟的人
You look like you do.
我抽烟  布朗先生
I do, Mr. Brown.
介意给我一支吗
Would you mind if I have one?
不  不介意
No, not at all.
那么
So, um...
开始自我介绍吧
let's go through and introduce ourselves.
谁想先来
Any volunteers?
那我先来  我叫理查德
I'll go first. My name is Richard.
是你们的老师  点吧
I'm your professor. Go ahead.
真他妈的不好抽
That was fucking wretched.
天呐
Jesus.
好了
Okay.
下一个是谁
Who's next?
你怎么样
How about you?
-我吗  -没错  你
- Me? - Yeah, you,
打电话的女孩
girl with the phone.
你是谁
Who are you,
我们为什么要认识你
why should we know you,
你的人生目标是什么
what do you want to do with your life?
好吧
Okay.
我是克莱尔
I'm Claire.
我来自纽约州北部
I'm from Upstate New York.
为什么要认识我
Why you should know me?
我也不知道
I don't know.
真的  我也不知道
Yeah. I don't know.
我猜  因为我叔叔是学校的校长
I guess because my uncle is the president of the school.
恶心  亨利·怀特是你叔叔吗
Ew. Henry Wright is your uncle?
-是的  -我受不了那个二货
- Yes. - I can't stand the fuck.
我也不太喜欢他
I don't really like him either.
很高兴听你这么说
That's very good to hear.
我想说  他真像个蜜桃冰淇淋
I mean, he's so peach melba.
既油腻又
Just slimy and...
我有主意了
I've got an idea.
先暂停一下这破课
How about we put a little pause to this shit
我们去酒吧
and we go down to the bar,
然后我们在那继续上
and we can run over it there.
我的亲生父亲是在波士顿
My biological father actually met my mothers
每月的堆肥会议上遇见我母亲的
at a monthly compost meeting in Boston.
他是个人类社会学家
He's this social anthropologist over at a...
很好  罗丝
Okay. Rose,
去给大家每人再拿两扎啤酒  好吗
go and grab two more pitchers for everybody, would you?
为什么不直接记在你的账上
Why don't you just put them in your tab?
不  这不是重点
No, that's not the point.
重点是  我想要你去拿
See, I want you to go and get them.
而且我想要你现在就去  拜托了
And I want you go and get them now, please?
我能要些鹰嘴豆泥吗
Can I get some hummus?
可以  买吧
Yeah, get some hummus.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我给你们一小点建议
Let me give you all a piece of advice.
如果这个人有一丁存心怀孕的倾向
Steer very clear of anyone who has even the faintest,
躲的远远的
slightest whip of intentional conception.
我爸妈是故意怀上我的
I was conceived intentionally.
好吧  我得知道你叫什么
Well, I need to know your name.
还有  希望你们父母都告诉你们了
By the way, I hope your parents all told you
人总有一天会死
that you fucking die at the end.
你会死的  你会死的
You're gonna die. You're gonna die.
你会死的  总有一天
You're gonna die. One day,
即使是无忧无虑的小罗丝也会死
even our blessed little Rose will die.
所以我在想  要是他妈的都没好好活过
So, what I'm wondering is, why the fuck do we
我们何苦要来这人世间走一遭
sort of float through this weird thing called life without living?
你知道  活着
You know, live.
不是存在  不是简单地存在
Don't exist. Don't simply exist.
那样太他妈无聊了  要活着
That's boring as fuck. Live.
你懂的  干些大事  操地惊天动地
You know. Stir some shit up. Fuck some shit up.
操得对  最重要的是丰富我们的生活
Fuck it right. What I wanna focus on is enriching our lives.
从中学到一些能受益终身的智慧
And try to extract some sort of wisdom that we can carry with us.
你懂得  而不仅仅是爸爸妈妈的累赘
You know, something other than mommy and daddy's baggage.
上帝祝福你  亲爱的
Ah, bless you, dear.
我想对你眨眨眼  可是我从来没学会
You know, I'd wink at you but I never learned how.
我觉得该解释一下
So I just thought you should know it.
还有人想要别的吗
Anybody want anything else?
我要  能给我拿杯威士忌吗
Yeah, could I get a whiskey?
当然可以
Oh, that's fine.
她冲我放电来着
She winked at me.
我买了鹰嘴豆泥了
I got the hummus, so...
你拯救了圣诞节
Christmas is saved.
天呐
My God.
来
Here we go.
愿我们能永远记住每一个
May we forever remember that in each and every moment,
我们谱写自己生命篇章的瞬间
we are composing the stories of our lives.
我们要努力让它成为一个有意义的故事
Let's aim to make it a meaningful read or at least,
至少是个有趣的故事
an interesting one, yeah?
来  干杯
All right. Cheers.
干杯
Cheers.
现在  不介意的话
Now, if you will excuse me,
我要去做点出轨的事了
I intend to explore a smidgen of infidelity.
什么情况啊
What the fuck?
好了  孩子们  玩得开心点
All right, kids. Have fun.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
-只管操我  -没问题
- Just fuck me. - Okay.
你根本不需要做任何选择
You don't have to make any choices at all.
我们可以包办一切  重新装修科技馆
We can cover it all. We could renovate science hall.
英语部再换些新椅子
We could bring in a new chair to the English department.
我说  那挺好的  不用我吩咐了
Well, I said, "Well, of course, that goes without saying."
你大学排名
Surely you have better...
肯定比我的要好
you know, college rankings than I.
闭嘴
Shut up.
天呐  维罗妮卡  那他妈的是啥
Jesus, Veronica. What the hell was that?
滚开
Fuck off.
让他们瞅着吧
Let them watch.
罗丝  嘴巴闭上
Rose, close your mouth.
你那样张着嘴非常不好看
It's unattractive when you gape like that.
小丹尼  帮我个忙
Danny boy, do me a favor.
吃完后结下帐
Uh, close out the tab when you're done.
然后  那啥
Yeah. And what... what...
不好意思  甜心  你叫什么来着
I'm sorry, what's your name again, sweetheart?
萨拉.
Sarah.
别忘了给萨拉留小费
Be sure and leave Sarah a healthy tip
因为她是个非常非常好的人
because it turns out she's a very, very nice person.
我们下周再见吧
I'll see you guys next week, yeah?
罗丝  我先拿你开刀
Oh, yeah, Rose. Let me get you out of the way first.
-回去好好准备一下  -但我不知道该怎么做
-So be prepared. -But I don't know what to do.
准备《白鲸》
Moby Dick. Moby Dick it is.
19世纪美国海洋题材小说  描写了亚哈船长为了追逐并杀死白鲸莫比·迪克
最终与白鲸同归于尽的故事
好主意  那先这样
Good idea. All right.
再见
Have a good one.
不到一分钟他就选中了女服务员
He just picked up that waitress in less than a minute.
到洗手间里上了她
And fucked her in the bathroom.
对  他们俩都是成年人
Yeah, well, they're both consenting adults,
可以为所欲为
so they can do whatever they want.
干杯
Cheers to that.
吉布斯  吉布斯  看
Jibbles, Jibbles, Jibbles, look.
我感觉妈咪正在偷腥
Look, I feel mommy is cheating.
说了啥
What's it say?
管用了
It works.
我们得试着阻止他
Let's go try to stop him
-免得他喝个烂醉  -皮特  别管了
from drinking so much. Oh. Peter, come on.
他自己开心就好
He's having a good time.
噢  理查德  你看起来很有精神
Ah, Richard, you're looking rather sprite.
我刚刚做爱没带套
Oh, I just had unprotected sex.
噢  跟谁啊
Oh, with who?
狮子酒吧非常甜的那个女服务员
Some very sweet girl from the Lion's Pub.
嗨  朵娜
Hello, Donna.
真恶心  他没必要跟我们说那个吧
Oh, that's disgusting. Why would he tell us that?
今天过得怎样啊  甜心
So, how was your day, sweetheart?
还行
Fine.
那挺好
Good. Fine's fine.
-泰勒怎样啊  -她很好
- How's Taylor? - She's fine.
那就更好了
That's even finer.
让我们为美好的日子干杯
Let us cheers to a fine day all round.
二位好
Hello.
维罗妮卡
Hmm, Veronica.
坐吧
Sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
太客气了
You're so welcome.
现在  我们再试一次  好吗
Now, let's give this another shot, shall we?
奥莉维亚  你妈妈想跟你道歉
Olivia, your mother would like to apologize.
是的  我很抱歉
Yes, I would like to apologize...
我那天的行为
for my behavior the other night.
我不知道为什么会作出那种反应
I don't know why my reaction was so, um...
不知道为什么那么的
I don't know.
右翼吗
Right wing?
右翼认为福利越多,人的依赖性就越强,进取心就越差
就会鼓励懒惰,打击勤奋,从而对一个国家的前途造成消极的影响
对
Yes.
我非常抱歉
I'm really sorry.
做得好
Beautiful.
奥莉维亚  你接受妈妈的道歉吗
Olivia, do you accept your mother's apology?
当然
Sure.
那就好
Well, good.
事情已经解决了
The matter's settled.
祝大家好胃口
Bon appetit.
以实玛利声称  一次环游世界的旅行
So, Ishmael claims that a journey around the world
《白鲸记》里的角色 在圣经旧约中是亚伯拉罕的长子
这个名字已经成为孤儿 流亡者和社会弃儿的象征
能把你带回到起始点
just brings you back to where you were before you started,
这实际上来自于一个男人
but this is actually coming from a man, who's lost everything
他失去了过去几年里
that's been his entire reality and consciousness
所有的现实和意识
for the past few years...
我看起来气色变好了吗
Do I look like I'm getting some color?
不知道  有点看不出来
I don't know. Hard to tell from here.
感觉最近气色变好了很多
It really feels like I'm getting some color.
有人要提问吗
Does anyone have any questions?
啥  噢  有有
What? Oh, uh, yes. Um...
概括一下
In a word?
复仇
Vengeance.
所以  你喜欢这个故事
So, you liked it?
是的  非常喜欢
Yeah. Yeah, I did.
然而  并没有宽肩膀的女人
And yet, there were no broad shouldered women lamenting,
从二层窗户里悲叹和哭泣  是吗
and sobbing out of second story windows, were there?
-没有  -不错
- No. - Good.
那意味着我们在打破
That means we're breaking down
你"合作"的性格
that co-op personality of yours.
我想我们可能会在本季度结束前
I think we're probably gonna get a bit of an edge out of you
把你逼出些棱角来
before the end of the quarter.
抱歉  什么
Excuse me?
你得了A-
You get an A minus.
这不坏啊
That's not a bad thing.
等我一下  孩子们
Just give me one second, kids.
我得再看一眼
I'm gonna have to take one more look
这个艺术死胎
at this artistic still born.
看呐  耶稣老天
Look at it, Jesus Christ,
很愚蠢的错误
it's a boner.
那是个非常愚蠢的错误
That is a gigantic boner.
-嗨  亲爱的  -那不是你妻子的作品吗
-Hi, honey. -Isn't that your wife's work?
是的  是的
Yeah, it is. It is.
这并不意味着我没意见
It doesn't mean I don't have an opinion on the matter.
谁
Who is it?
我是丹尼尔·怀特
Uh, it's Daniel Wright.
进来吧
Come on in.
音乐不错
Nice music.
以为你会听些其他风格的呢
Thought you'd be listening something different.
是吗  什么风格的
Really, like what exactly?
不知道
I don't know. Uh,
巴迪·霍利
Buddy Holly?
美国摇滚音乐歌手  1936-1959
天呐  你到底觉得我有多少岁
Jesus, uh, uh, how old do you think I am?
六十左右吗
Maybe around 60.
真他妈令人沮丧
That's fucking depressing.
-对不起  我  -不  不用道歉
-I'm sorry. I... -No. No. No.
你说出了想法  没关系  过来吧
You spoke your mind, it's all right. Come on in.
好吧  我给你带了点东西
Well, I brought you some pot.
不会吧
No.
我给你做了些布朗宁加料蛋糕
I made you some brownies.
添加大麻烘焙的蛋糕
你真贴心
Wow. That's very kind of you.
我应该给你多少钱
How, uh, how much do I owe you?
算我的  如果你还想要
It's on the house. If you want more,
价格可以再谈
we can talk prices later.
干啊  谢谢你
Fuck me. Thank you very much.
-不客气  -谢谢
- You're welcome. - Thank you.
你介意我问个私人问题吗
You mind if I ask you something personal?
不介意  问吧
No, go ahead.
你和男人在一起过吗
Have you ever been with a man?
不  没有  没
No. Nope. Nope. Nope.
不  应该是没有的
No, I can't say that I have.
你可以操我吗
Would you like to fuck me?
呃
Like...
-从你后门吗  -是的
- in your ass? - Yeah.
-这  干净吗  -是啊  我想应该是
- Is it... is it clean? - Yeah. I mean it should be.
不过  我随时都可以给你吹箫
But no. I mean, I can always give you blowjob, too.
好吧  再给我倒一杯
Okay. Pour me another one of those
倒满吧  因为我
and make it very generous because I'm...
-当然可以  -真的不知道
- Of course. - ...really not sure how much
这段对话我想要记得多少
of this I'm gonna wanna remember.
谢谢
Thank you.
所以  我还没  我是说  我不能
So, like, there's no... I mean, couldn't...
我们没必要接吻  对吧
we don't have to kiss, right?
没有亲吻  不  哇
There's no kissing. No. Wow.
是因为我们是男孩吗
Is it like 'cause we're boys?
-是啊  -噢  好吧
- Yeah. - Oh, okay.
今天我们聚集在一起
And so we're gathered to dedicate...
为当代杰出艺术家之一的作品举行落成典礼
the work of one of the finest contemporary artists of today,
我很荣幸能成为她的朋友
and someone that I am honored to call a dear friend,
-有请维罗妮卡·辛克莱尔·布朗女士  -做得好
- Mrs. Veronica Sinclair Brown. - Well done.
-这么明目张胆  -真美
- It's blatantly foul. - Beautiful.
这还  挺棒的
It's, uh, wonderful.
哦  太好了
Oh, that's great.
我能问问  这是什么吗
May I ask what is it?
就是个巨型鸡巴
It's a giant schmeckle.
依地语 犹太人使用的国际语
我们非常感激
We appreciate it so much.
-很幸运能有你在  -容我失陪
- We're lucky to have you. - Would you excuse me?
-你觉得如何  -噢
- What do you think? - Oh.
我妈说不允许我去公立学校
Um, mom says I'm not allowed to go to state schools.
不允许你妈说不允许你去
Your mom is not allowed to say you're not allowed.
但最好还是别去公立学校了
It's probably best if you don't.
别听他的  听我的
Don't listen to him. Listen to me.
杰出的作品
Splendid work, truly.
-谢谢你  皮特  -不用谢
- Thank you, Peter. - Yeah.
奥莉  你觉得如何
What do you think, Olive?
呃  很不错  挺好的
The... uh, it was... yeah, it was good.
还行
It's all right, yeah.
我们喝点酒庆祝一下吧
So, shall we have a celebratory drink?
我很想去  但亨利邀请我和捐助者
I'd love to, but Henry has me going out to dinner
共进晚餐  是康涅狄格州的一位世家赞助者
with the benefactors. It's an old money from Connecticut.
家里见
Oh. I'll see you two at home.
再见  甜心  感谢  皮特
Bye, sweetie. Thanks, Peter.
你确定不想来点
Are you sure you don't want
伏特加或者布朗宁吗
a little splash of vodka or brownie?
你为什么和妈妈依旧在一起呢
Why are you and mom still together?
好吧
Yeah.
这问题倒是挺奇怪的
That's a rather odd question.
不  一点都不奇怪
No, it's not.
好吧  没错  我们
And I guess you're right, we... um...
我觉得随着年龄的增长
I think as you get older,
你就会发现自己需要一个
you, um, find yourself needing someone
完全信赖的人一起过日子
to hold accountable for life
而且不会是你想象当中的样子
not turning out exactly as you'd imagined it.
天呐  爸
Jesus, dad.
我知道
I know.
听我说  并不是所有人际关系都得那样
But listen to me, not every relationship has to be that.
我是说  大多数是
I mean, having said that, most are.
好吧
Okay.
说点开心的  你和泰勒怎么样了
On that happy note. How's it going with Taylor?
处得很不错
It's going really well.
真的吗  那就好
Yeah? Good, that's good.
那就好
That's very good.
你恋爱了吗
Are you in love?
是的
Yeah. I am.
哇  真的吗
Wow. No shit.
我真为你开心  甜心
Yeah, well, I'm happy for you, sweetheart.
真的很为你开心
I'm so happy. I'm so happy for you.
谢谢爸爸
Thanks.
你要确定她知道你有多珍贵
You make sure she understands your worth.
-我确定  她知道的  -最好是
- I know. She does. - She better.
她该死的最好是知道
She damn well better.
你女儿恋爱了
Your daughter is in love.
你告诉她要小心点吗
Did you tell her to be careful?
没有
No.
我告诉她尽情享受
Told her to enjoy herself.
知天命是生而为人的唯一要务
To realize one's destiny is a person's only obligation.
第三章
我是真的快死了
呃  然后  他开始倾听沙漠
Uh, and so, uh, he begins listening to the desert,
发现世间万物的灵魂
and, uh discovering the soul of the world,
这不可避免的会  指引我们
which then inevitably, uh, leads us to...
很好  停下
All right, stop.
给你B
You get a B.
-但我还没讲完  -请坐下
- But I'm not finished. - Take a seat.
我觉得讲得很好
I thought it was great.
问你个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你们觉得这些狗屁有用吗
Are you guys getting anything out of this shit?
有
Yeah.
很好  因为我不得不说  我也觉得
Good. Because I have to say, I am as well.
我想说  你们是成年的年轻群体
I mean, you're all rather a solid group of young adults,
我喜欢和你们在一起
and I enjoy your company.
没错  我得说我们确实挺成熟的
Yeah. Yeah, uh, I'd say we're all pretty mature.
成熟  其实就是另外一个词
Well, maturity is really just another word for...
来表示你能忍受多大痛苦
how much misery you'd swallow.
是的  完全正确
Yeah, totally.
我说的是别人带给你的痛苦  罗丝
I'm talking about the piss and shit of others, Rose,
而不是你自己本身的
not your own.
介意我抽支大麻吗
Do you mind if I smoke a joint?
谢谢
Thanks.
我非常愿意帮他代课
I'm more than happy to help, uh, pick up his classes,
如果这能帮上点忙的话
if that helps at all.
这是在开玩笑吧
You got to be kidding me.
他是在抽大麻烟吗
Is he smoking a marijuana cigarette?
呃  可能他只是  呃
Uh, look, um, maybe he's just trying to be...
真他妈难以置信
Fucking unbelievable.
理查德
Richard.
你为什么戴着墨镜
Why are you wearing sunglasses?
我有癌症
I have cancer,
我理应在不合适的场合戴墨镜
I'm supposed to wear sunglasses in unusual places.
好吧
Yeah.
劳驾  能再给我们来两杯吗
Excuse me, can we have two more please?
呃  不用了  买单好了
Uh, no, uh, the check please.
为什么
Why?
听着  你得跟我走
Look, you're coming with me.
我不想跟你走
I don't wanna go with you.
皮特  我们要去哪儿
Peter, where are we going?
带你去互助小组
I'm taking you to support group.
干嘛的互助小组
A support group for what?
癌症  我的天
Cancer. Oh, Jesus.
学术休假的时候  想让我帮你代课吗
Want me to help you with your sabbatical,
那你就为我去  这对我来说也不容易
then do this for me. This is not easy for me,
应该说是非常困难
it's actually, it's quite hard.
我理解  但是  要死的人是我
Uh, I understand that, but, you know, it's my death.
是啊
Yeah.
这他妈是什么
What the fuck is this?
呃  是芭芭拉的
Well, it's, uh, it's Barbara's.
恶心  我可不进去
Eww. Um, I'm not getting in.
闭嘴  给老子上车
Shut up, and get in the damn car.
这车其实挺好开的
It actually drives quite nice.
开门
Door.
-好了  -不错
- Here you go. - Well done.
我们结婚二十年了  我本以为
After 20 years of marriage, I thought she'd, you know,
她会一直陪着我  直到我离开人世
stick around until I died.
至少我希望她会这样
At least, I hoped she would.
但是  也许没这个必要吧
But, I guess, it was really no point,
也许  对她来说
you know, I guess it makes more sense for her
忘记过去向前看  才是最合适的
to move on now.
但是尽管如此
But despite all that, I'm-I'm...
我  我还是挺好的
I'm feeling pretty good.
我还不错
I'm doing okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你跟我们分享你战斗的故事  艾德
Thank you for sharing the journey of your battle, Ed.
好  准备好就可以开始了
All right. Whenever you're ready.
呃  我叫皮特  我很健康
Uh, my name is Peter, I'm healthy,
我没得癌症
I don't have cancer,
至少我觉得自己没事
at least I don't think I do.
我朋友
my friend,
理查德有癌症
Richard does.
我觉得他应该来这里聊聊这件事
And I thought that he could here and talk about it.
我
I'm...
很害怕
scared,
很担心
I'm worried,
我不想失去我最好的朋友
I don't wanna lose my best friend.
皮特  你这样真的很暖心
That is really very lovely of you, Peter.
感谢你给我们分享你
Thank you for sharing the journey of your...
战斗的故事
battle.
好  理查德
All right, Richard.
准备好了随时开始
Whenever you're ready.
不不不  我不参加这个  不不
Oh, no, no, no. I'm not doing this. No, no.
-来嘛  -我没什么要说的
- Come on. - I have nothing to say.
这对你有好处
It's good for you.
嗯  要不  从你的诊断结果开始讲行吗
Uh, well, um, why don't you start with your diagnosis?
啊  还是不了吧
Uh, I'd rather not,
其实我想走了
I'd actually prefer to leave this place
因为这里的光线太暗
because the lighting is poor down here,
闻起来就跟便池除臭剂和甜饼干一样
and it smells like urinal cakes and sugar cookies.
呃  你会发现如果你
Uh, well, you find that if you...
如果你从诊断结果开始讲起
if you start with your diagnosis...
我觉得你会发现  我已经知道
I think that you're gonna find that I already know
我不同意你所说的任何话
that I disagree with whatever you're about to say.
皮特我们走吧  我们下次再试
Peter, let's go. We'll give it another shot.
有没有人想一起喝一杯
Would anyone else like to go and grab a drink,
逃离这个情感呆圈
and escape this emotional circle jerk?
你要去吗
What about you?
你可能需要喝几杯
You might need a drink or two.
理查德  我得癌症了
Richard, I... I've got cancer.
我也是啊
So do I.
好吧  祝即将死去的你们好运
Well, best of luck with your impending deaths.
-你也是哦  -谢谢
- Yeah, you, too. - Thank you.
理查德  你得留下来  我想帮你
Oh, Richard, you gotta stay. Uh, I wanna help you.
皮特  不
Peter, no.
要是我死在这里
I'd die here, and my corpse
我的尸体只会成为滋养寄生虫的温床
is nothing more than a breeding ground for ticks.
而且我这么离开的话
Plus, this way,
终局之前  我还能一直领工资
I get to collect my salary until the bitter end.
甚至死了之后也行
Maybe even after, depending on
取决于什么时候能找到  呃  我的尸体
how quickly it takes me to find, my, uh, body.
我必须走
I have to leave for, uh...
这是为了奥莉维亚好
for Olivia's sake.
别啊
No.
别别别  听我说
Oh, no, no, come on. Listen.
好了  我要
Uh, yeah. All right. I'm gonna...
-我真的很遗憾  -我知道
- I am so sorry. - I know.
我的朋友
My friend.
理查德
Oh, Richard.
听我说
Listen to me.
我觉得是时候出发去加拿大了
I think it's time to go up to Canada.
-不  我不  -是的
- No. I don't... - Yeah.
皮特  你知道别人在议论我俩吗
Peter, you know they're talking about us.
嗨  布朗教授
Hi. Hello, Professor Brown.
-嗨克莱尔  -你在这干嘛呢
- Hey, Claire. - What are you doing here?
-你好  -你好
- Nice to see you. - Nice to see you.
这是克莱尔
This is... Claire, uh...
这是克莱尔  这是皮特
This is Claire and this is Peter.
-嗨  -你好
- Hi. - Nice to see you.
她  实际上是亨利·怀特的侄女
She's, in fact, a niece of Henry Wright.
亨利  亨利  啊太好了
Henry, Henry? Oh, how wonderful.
太好了  很高兴认识你
That's great, good to meet you.
不用说这些屁话  因为她和我们一样鄙视他
You don't have to say that shit because she despises him as much as we do.
别这样说
Don't say things like that.
他挺好的  亨利·怀特
He's all right, Henry Wright.
他是个特别好的人
He's perfectly right.
麻烦再给我倒三杯
I'll have another three please.
-我不想走  -不行
- No, I don't want go. - No, no, you're...
-我正开心呢  -你举止已经像个山怪了
- I'm having fun. - You're behaving like a troll.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
有人跟你说过  你很美吗
Has anyone ever told you that you're beautiful?
谢谢  皮特
Thank you, Peter.
好孩砸
Good boy.
行了  够了  上车吧
Okay. That's it. Okay. Get in the car. Just get...
嘿  我能请你喝杯睡前酒吗
Hey, can I, uh, buy you a nightcap?
睡前酒
Nightcap?
芭芭拉会杀了我的
Hmm. Barbara's gonna kill me.
要是我说不行  你是不是特失望
Would you be disappointed if I said no?
这是辆迷你库珀吗
Was it a Mini Cooper?
会的
Yes.
-晚安  皮特  -晚安
- Goodnight, Peter. - Night.
-理查德  -干嘛
- Richard? - Yeah.
爱你哟
Love you.
我想说  我特别佩服你的勇气
I'd like to say how much I admire your bravery.
关于什么的勇气
Bravery for what?
做你自己
For being who you are,
毫无畏惧地做你自己
and doing so, unflinchingly.
这不是勇敢  是冷漠
That's not bravery, that's apathy.
不  不是的
No, it's not.
我去点首歌放放
I'm gonna go put on some music.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
不
no.
我不好
No, I'm not.
我得癌症了
I got cancer.
没关系的  我这个年纪的人都有癌症
It's all right. Everyone my age has cancer.
不知为何  我一直没能理解这意味着什么
For some reason, it just never really kind of...
直到
hit until...
此时此刻
now, what it really means.
因为我会死的
You know, because I'm gonna die.
是真的快死了
I mean, I'm really gonna die.
很抱歉  理查德
I'm sorry, Richard.
帮我个忙  别把这件事告诉别人行吗
Do me a favor, please keep that between us, yeah?
好
Okay.
除了皮特以外
You're the only person I've ever told,
你是唯一一个知道的
outside of Peter.
我还没告诉我妻子和女儿
Haven't even told my wife and daughter yet.
和我跳支舞吧
Come dance with me.
跳舞
Dance?
我不跳舞
I don't dance.
今晚跳一下吧
Dance tonight.
好
Okay.
♪ 我啊 ♪
♪ And I ♪
♪ 从未拥有过谁 ♪
♪ Never have no one ♪
♪ 在逆境之中 ♪
♪ In times of trouble ♪
♪ 我也孑然一身 ♪
♪ I stood alone ♪
我现在该干嘛
What do I do now?
♪ 而如今 ♪
♪ And now ♪
♪ 我愈发坚强 ♪
♪ I'm so much stronger... ♪
就这样吗
Is this it?
对啊
Uh-hmm.
呃  好吧
Well, okay.
♪ 你的爱是忧郁的蓝色 ♪
♪ Your love is blue ♪
很糟糕吗
Is this so bad?
不
No.
这样其实挺好的
No, this is actually quite nice.
♪ 当困难将你压倒 ♪
♪ When trouble overtakes you ♪
♪ 你应该再次思考 ♪
♪ You better check again ♪
♪ 可如今我的生活已更加明朗 ♪
♪ But now my days Gotten brighter ♪
理查德
Richard?
♪ 因为有你在身旁 ♪
♪ With you by my side ♪
理查德
Richard.
救命啊  嘿  嘿
Help. Hey, hey, hey.
救命
Help!
我的老天爷啊  理查德
Oh, Jesus Christ, Richard.
到底发生了什么
What the hell happened?
我很好  冷静  别
I'm all right, just calm down. Don't...
一切都很好  我很好
Everything's fine, I'm all right.
我没死  我挺好的
I didn't die. I'm good.
这是谁
Well, who's that?
是圣地亚哥
That's Santiago.
圣地亚哥是谁
Who's Santiago?
我的园丁
He's my gardener.
你园丁在这干啥呢
What's your gardener doing here?
他是我的紧急联系人
He's my emergency contact.
我天  理查德
Christ, Richard
呃  我们能私下聊两句吗
Um, can we have a word in private please?
没关系的  他根本不会讲英语
No, that's fine, he doesn't speak any English.
看
Watch this.
圣地亚哥  今天周几
Santiago, what day is it?
看见没  煎饼
See? Pancakes
嗯啊  劳伦·白考尔
Yes, Lauren Bacall.
好莱坞传奇女演员
说吧  你刚才想说什么  没关系的
Talk. What are you gonna say? It's fine.
理查德  你不能再这样下去了
Richard, you've got to clean up your act.
是啊  我搞砸了  我会少摄入点糖
Yeah. I fucked up. I'll slow down the candy,
环保一点点  好吗
and I'll go green for a bit, okay?
-卖草吗  -对啊  大麻
- Selling grass? - Marijuana, yeah.
你从哪儿搞的大麻呢
Oh, and where are you getting it?
一个学生那  他叫丹尼
Student of mine. His name is Danny.
很好的一个孩子  特特特聪明
Really good kid, very, very, very smart kid.
听着  我不想让你像个小屁孩一样
Look, I don't want you dying over something
死于吸毒过量  好吗
as infantile as an overdose, okay?
我要走了
I'm gonna go out.
不然就会在医院染上什么病的
Oh, or you'll catch something in the hospital.
好吧  我们  呃  我们学校见
Oh, okay. Well, I'll see you back on, uh, on the campus.
好
Yeah.
我们学校见
I'll see you back on campus.
你说过了  走吧皮特  谢谢你来看我
Yeah, you said, just go, Pete. Thanks for coming by.
你看起来挺好的  挺好的
Yeah, you're looking good, you're looking good.
你觉得我看起来像病了吗
Do I look sick to you?
你躺的是病床呢  理查德
You're in a hospital bed, Richard.
不打算告诉我昨晚去哪了吗
You wanna say where you were last night?
不打算
Not really.
为了奥莉维亚  我俩说好的
We had a deal for Olivia.
我知道
I know.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事儿  背不舒服
Yeah. It's just my back.
理查德
Richard?
在呢
Yes?
抱歉  没听到你说话
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't hear you answer.
我是卡萝  亨利的秘书
Uh, it's Carol, Henry's secretary.
理查德  亨利想和你谈谈
Uh, Richard, Henry would like to have a word with you.
-什么时候  -现在
- When? - Now.
告诉他我很忙
Tell him I'm busy.
他说是要紧事
He says the matter is rather urgent.
告诉他我也有要紧事
Tell him I'm urgently busy.
理查德
Richard.
在
Yes?
他可以见你了
He's ready to see you now.
理查德  你喜欢鱼吗
Tell me, Richard, do you like fish?
不喜欢  有时候吃一点
No. I mean to eat sometimes,
仅此而已
but outside of that, no. No, I don't.
我认为人们可以从鱼身上学到很多东西
I believe men could learn a lot from fish.
这是我听过最愚蠢的事了
That's the most asinine thing I've ever heard.
为什么不有话直说呢
Why don't we just cut to the chase?
好吧
All right.
我收到了一些针对你的指责
We need to talk about certain allegations
引起了我的注意
that have come to my attention,
其中有一些说的很严重
some of which are serious.
别了  闭嘴
Don't even start.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你听的清清楚楚
I know you heard what I said.
你是故意想让我重复
You're simply saying that for effect.
好话不说二遍  我是不会
You want me to repeat myself, I won't.
我是这所大学的校长
I am chancellor of this university.
你他妈算个毛球
I couldn't give a fucking rat's balls
你算什么屌东西  我有终身教职
who the fuck you are. I have tenure,
此外
and furthermore,
我们之间  你没有任何立场可言
you're in no position of power when it comes to the two of us.
你背着老婆乱搞  亨利
You're cheating on your wife, Henry.
你搞外遇  而且不是一般的外遇
You're having an affair, and not just any affair,
是和本校敬业教职人员的老婆
but one with a wife of a devoted faculty member,
具体地说是
specifically
我老婆
mine.
不仅如此  你还从已经缩小的经费里
Not only that. But you've allocated funds
挪出一部分用来建造校园里
from a dwindling budget for granite erections
你刚剪彩的那个"勃起"的花岗岩垃圾
that you just littered throughout this entire campus.
更巧的是  这些垃圾出自
And oddly enough, they come from the woman
那个和你通奸的女人
that you're bird dogging on the side.
你能跟我说说
Can you remind me
维罗妮卡的一件作品到底值多少钱
how much does one of Veronica's works go for?
校长大人  你那些破事儿我了如指掌
Chancellor, I have mounted you like a running stag,
今天我打开天窗说亮话
and I am pumping away at you, like a savage,
你无话可说吧
and you know it.
还有
Now,
我默认我的学术休假申请通过了
I'm gonna take it that my request for sabbatical has been accepted.
第四章
感觉慢慢上来了
别看起来太热情
Don't look so enthusiastic.
为什么要很热情
Why would I?
好吧  首先  人家请了专人承办酒席
Well, for one, it's gonna be catered.
芭芭拉只会说她旅行有多好
All Barbara ever talks about is how well traveled she is.
不然她还能说啥
Well, what else would she talk about?
谢谢你  亲爱的
Thank you, dear.
伊维萨岛的空气
The air in Ibiza,
西班牙巴利阿里群岛中的岛屿  因其丰富的夜生活和电子音乐闻名于世
真是无与伦比
there's really nothing like it.
光是想起来  就能感觉到雾气了
I'm getting misty, just thinking about it.
皮特  把旅行社的联系方式发给大家吧
Peter, put our agent in touch with them, all right?
好啊  我很乐意
Yes, of course, yes, I'd be happy to.
理查德
Richard?
理查德  怎么了
Richard, what's the matter?
亲爱的  不用管他
Uh, darling, let him be.
就像我说的  伊维萨岛不会让你后悔
Anyway, as I was saying, Ibiza...
你还好吗
Are you all right?
我很好
I'm more than all right.
我非常好
I'm perfect.
除非你疯了
I mean, unless you're mad.
我说得对吧  皮特
Am I right or what, Peter?
你说得对  亲爱的
Oh, you're right, darling, you're right.
还有谁在鱼里吃到了鱼刺
Does anybody else have bones in the fish?
我们来一起庆祝
We have something to celebrate.
庆祝什么  你也得了癌症
What's that? You got cancer, too?
我才没有  你为什么老这么说
No. I do not. Why do you keep saying that?
我的囊肿  经常很痛
Uh, I... my cyst is rather sore.
是你喉咙里的吗
Uh-oh, something in your throat?
我觉得可能要去照个片子看看
I think I should get it screened.
-可能要的  -是啊
- Maybe. - Yeah. Yeah.
理查德  不  不
Uh, Richard, uh, no, no, no,
她会更起劲儿
that'll only encourage her.
我们会注意到这会
...we've noticed that it's allowed us
让我们对自身  有新的发现
every time we've been to discover something new about ourselves.
你  我的朋友  可以学术休假了
You, my friend, have been awarded a sabbatical.
谢谢
Thank you.
亨利·怀特上周签字同意了
Henry Wright signed the paperwork, only last week.
看  我就说会这样
See, I told you.
你们两个在干什么
What are you two doing?
我们在讨论工作
Uh we're discussing work. That's all.
彼得  今天是我的生日
Peter, it's my birthday,
工作以后再聊  过来一起聊
save it for another time, and come mingle.
好的
All right.
别再关门了
And don't close these doors.
不关了  亲爱的
No, darling.
当时  彼得被吓呆了
Anyway, Peter was petrified...
我们结婚到底为了什么
Why the hell did we ever get married?
你还好吗
You okay?
我很好  宝贝
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine, babe.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
是啊
Yeah.
我不会有事的
Yeah. I'm gonna be fine.
你一开始爱的人
The person one loves at first
不是你最终的爱人
is not the person one loves at last.
爱不是一个结果
Love is not an end,
而是一个过程  一个尝试
it's a process through, which one person attempts
了解彼此的过程
to know another.
我说完了
That's it.
总结一下
And in a word?
一言以蔽之  言浅意深
In two words, deceptively simple.
漂亮  完成的很漂亮
Beautifully, beautifully executed.
给这节课画上圆满句号
And it's a really nice way to end the class with a little,
直击心灵
kick in the ass.
给你A
So, you get an A.
-谢谢您  -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
你们其他人都在等着我
And I suppose the rest of you are waiting
吐出一些深奥的智慧之言
for me to vomit out some profound words of wisdom.
是的  等着呢
Yeah, kind of.
还以为你不会问呢
Oh, thought you'd never ask.
过来  帮我一把
Come here, give me a hand.
谢谢
Thanks.
世界需要你们这样的人
the world needs people like you.
像你们这样的人越来越少
The world is literally dying for your kind.
担负责任  勇敢奋斗
Embrace that responsibility, and you run with it.
迈出第一步  去争取  然后回馈
Get out there, earn your keep. Give back.
这不会很容易  永远都不会
It's not gonna be easy. Never gonna be easy.
大部分情况下  你会独自一人
For much of it, you'll stand alone
但请坚定信念
but you've got to stand strong.
我恳请大家
You know, I beg you
永远不要像这世上其他98%的人一样
to not give into mediocrity,
向平庸屈服
like the other 98 percent of the world.
因为平庸是对你自己
Because you would be doing yourselves,
和这个世界最大的伤害
and the world, a greatest disservice.
你们充满知识和智慧
You're all too smart.
不能白白浪费
You're too smart to let it go to waste.
你只有一次机会
And you've got one shot at this.
一次稍纵即逝的机会
One fucking shot.
紧紧抓牢 绝不放过
Don't let a moment of it slip by.
抓住它  抢过来  变成你的机会
Grab it, snatch it up, make it yours.
珍惜每时每刻
Celebrate every moment.
珍惜每一次呼吸
Celebrate every fucking breath.
我告诉你  生活
I'm telling you, life,
是一首赞歌
it's a birdsong.
就这些吗
Was that it?
是的  我觉得是
Yeah, I think... I think so, yeah.
就是这些了
Yeah, that's it.
理查德  理查德
Richard? Richard.
理查德
Oh, oh, Richard.
理查德  你还好吧
Oh, no, no, no. Richard, are you all right?
天呐
Christ.
-天使  -什么
- Angels. - What?
我听到天使在唱歌  皮特
I hear the angels, Peter, they're singing.
不  那是无伴奏合唱  理查德
No, that's the... that's the acapella group, Richard.
来
Here.
我们哪儿来的无伴奏合唱
Why? Why do we have an acapella group?
学校一直都有啊
We've always had an acapella group.
好吧  干  能带我去教堂吗
Well, fuck them. Can you take me to the bells?
我想去看看那些钟楼
What? I wanna see the bells.
教堂  好的
The bells? Yeah.
好  走吧
All right. All right. Come.
你先给我喝点水
I'll get you some water first.
皮特
Peter,
这里地方这么大  坐哪里都很舒服
there are a lot of other good places to sit in here.
呃  是的  当然
Hmm, yes. Of course.
你感觉到什么没吗
Can you feel anything?
没
No.
但我觉得这里光线不错
But I enjoy the lighting.
-你呢  -也没
- You? - No.
但这样也挺好
But that's all right.
圣母玛利亚  请保佑我的朋友
Please mother of God, help my friend...
恐怕  病的越来越重了
Afraid it's starting to kick in.
疼吗
Does it hurt?
他妈的  真疼
Oh, fuck yeah.
我很抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry.
我还能承受
I'll manage.
没事  皮特  该来的总会来
It's fine, Peter. We knew this was coming.
是啊
Yeah.
我回顾过往
I mean, uh, I look back on everything,
很多事情一下就都看明白了
and it all somehow makes so much sense.
一切好像  都是最好的安排
It's as though, uh, it couldn't be any other way.
为什么我们的灵魂会受伤
Why's our soul broken?
简直荒唐
Absurd.
但
Yet...
又如此完美
It's perfect.
回顾过往  一切又都很完美
And it's also perfect when you look at it.
-你懂我的意思吗  -我懂
- You know what I mean? - Yeah.
这个世界真让人不舍
It's gonna be hard to leave this place.
很难说再见
It's gonna be hard to say goodbye.
理查德  我会想你的
Richard, I'm gonna miss you.
如果可能  我也会想念你
I'm gonna miss you too, Peter. If I'm able.
妈的  我忍不住了
Fuck, I'm going to cry.
你这样我更难受
Please don't do this. No, no, shh.
-天啊  -不要这样  听着
- Dammit. - No, no, no. Listen.
我更希望你能别哭
I really prefer if you didn't cry.
听我说  我们努力过了
Listen to me. We tried.
-是的  - 我们走吧
- Yes. Yes. - Now let's go. Come on.
来吧
Come on.
好
Okay.
-抱歉  -来吧
- I'm sorry. - Come on.
没事
It's all right.
走吧  彼得
Come on, Peter.
理查德  你是个好人
You're a good man, Richard.
你也是  老朋友
So are you, my friend.
感谢你真诚待我
Thank you for being so good to me.
我在努力  理查德  忍着不哭
I'm trying, Richard. I'm trying.
感觉这么自然  难道不奇怪吗
Isn't it strange how natural this feels?
是啊  两个男人
Yeah. Two men,
在教堂里  热情相拥
holding one another, passionately, in a church.
毫无顾忌地互相抚摸
Groping one another freely.
走吧  死变态
Come on you, pervert.
拜拜
Bye.
你今晚要出去吗
You're going out tonight?
嗯
Yeah.
好的
OK.
玩得开心点
You have fun, okay?
你也是
Yeah, you, too.
会不会开心不知道  但我保证
I'm not sure that's possible, but I'm promising you
我们尽量
that we will try.
去吧  孩子
Go get 'em, kid.
再见  爸爸
Bye, dad.
第五章
我还有些话想说
非常感谢你能来
Thank you so much for coming, really.
一年比一年可人了
Oh, oh, you get just lovelier every year.
维罗妮卡  理查德 我们的贵宾
Veronica, Richard. Our guest of honor.
你能来真好
So nice you could make it.
我们怎么能错过
Oh, we wouldn't miss it for the world.
你好  我是理查德
How do you do? Hi, I'm Richard.
这他妈算哪门子问好
That's a hell of a greeting.
我去拿酒了
I'm going to the bar.
你好
Hi.
我和皮特决定今年留下来
Peter and I have decided to stay in this year,
在迈阿密度过圣诞节
and spend Christmas in Miami.
哦  赶时髦啊
Oh, how fashionable.
朵娜  你为什么没来参加我的生日宴会
Donna, you weren't at my birthday party. Why?
我一直想跟你解释
I've been so wanting to tell you
我把日期记错了
that I mixed up the date. Oh.
各位  请注意
Excuse me everyone, if I could have your attention.
晚宴很快就要开始了
Dinner is to be served shortly, so, if you would be so kind
现在各位就可以移驾去餐厅了
as to begin migrating to the dining room,
非常感谢
that would be much appreciated.
维罗妮卡  你坐我旁边
Veronica. You'll be right here next to me.
理查德
Richard.
不  不  恐怕座位太挤了
Uh, no, no, no. Tight Quarters, I'm afraid.
他可以坐到那边去
He'll be somewhere in the back.
大家好
Hello, everyone.
抱歉  为什么理查德不坐这张桌子
Um, sorry, why isn't Richard sitting at this table?
向你们保证  今晚的座位安排
I can assure you that there has been a great deal of thought
是经过深思熟虑的
that's going into the seating arrangements.
什么
What?
没了  死了
Dead, gone.
哦  太可怕了  什么原因
Oh, that's horrible. What was it?
恐怕是黑色素瘤
Oh, melanoma, I'm afraid.
欢迎这位年轻人
Oh. Oh, welcome, young man.
那他家人呢
And the families?
说实话
Honestly,
-你不会想知道的  -有那么可怕吗
- you don't wanna know. - Oh, really?
趁大家用餐时间
While everyone's being served,
我想说几句话
I just wanted to say a couple words.
我代表自己和我迷人的妻子  欢迎大家
On behalf of both myself and my lovely wife, welcome.
很荣幸能请到各位
It's an honor to have each
来参加今晚的宴会
and every one of you here tonight.
相信大家也跟我一样
Now, I know I'm not alone when I say that this quarter
度过了非常愉快的一个季度
may have been our very best.
能够有这么一个机会
And the opportunity to serve,
担任校长
as your president and chancellor,
我深感荣幸
has been nothing short of humbling.
因此  非常感谢你们
So thank you.
希望大家
I can only hope
能够达到各自制定的最终目标
to live up to the high standards that you have set.
干杯
Cheers.
现在  夜幕初降  请大家用餐
Now, let us eat for the night is young.
讲得很好
Oh, that was a lovely speech.
非常好
Beautiful.
真的吗  你吃这一套
Did you actually buy that shit, really?
你说什么
Excuse me?
你是在信息部吗
Are you in the communications department?
我有些话想要说
I have something that I would like to say.
你可以停一会儿吗
Could you stop playing that
在我把刀往那边扔之前
before I heave this knife in your direction?
谢谢
Thank you.
拿着酒瓶的那位年轻女士
Uh, young lady with the wine, would you mind
可以站在我旁边不要离开吗
just standing right by my side, and never leave?
因为我有很多话要讲
Because I have much to say
-还有很多祝词要说  -我的天
- and many to toast. - Oh, my God.
在场不认识我的人  我叫理查德·布朗
Those of you who do not know, my name is Richard Brown.
英文教授
Professor of English.
敬自己一杯
Oh, uh, cheers to me.
干杯
Cheers.
为理查德干杯
Cheers. To Richard.
亨利·怀特  我代表在座的每一位
Henry Wright, on behalf of every one of us here,
表达我们的感激之情
let me, please, express our gratitude,
为这美好的强迫前来的夜晚
for this finely forced evening.
你对学生  教职人员
The commitment that you have shown
甚至教职人员的妻子所作出的奉献
to the students, faculty, even the wives of the faculty...
令人印象非常深刻
...is very, very impressive.
你超越了自我
You've outdone yourself.
实践出真知
And it shows.
就我而言  三个卵蛋
As far as I'm concerned, three balls...
值得敬三次
deserves three cheers.
好了  理查德  我想这应该够了
All right, Richard, I think that's enough.
亨利  别打断我说话
Henry, do not interrupt me while I'm talking.
尤其当着这么多人的面
Particularly in front of so many people.
-你懂吗  -不  我不懂
- Do you understand? - No, I don't understand.
你懂
Yeah.
没人能有三个睾丸
Nobody has three testicles.
敬皮特·马修一杯
To Peter Matthew.
他该闭嘴了
Gotta shut up.
你拥有一颗金子般的心
Your heart is truly one of gold.
-没错  -这所大学
- It is. - And this college is...
能有你在非常幸运
very lucky to have you.
感谢你一直以来的努力
Of course, thank you for your hard work.
最重要的是  感谢你
But most important, thank you
能够成为我真正的好朋友
for being a true friend.
敬皮特  干杯
Oh, to Peter, cheers. Cheers.
敬皮特
To Peter.
我觉得我还欠你们一些道别的话
Also there are some parting words that I feel like I owe.
因为这将会是我最后一次见到你们
Because this will be the last time that I ever see any of you.
不仅因为我得到了学术休假
For not only have I been awarded a sabbatical, um...
他怪怪的
This is strange
我快要死了
...I'm gonna die.
对
Yeah...
我快要死了
I'm gonna die,
死的要比我预想的快得多
and I'm gonna die much sooner than I had imagined.
噢  我的天呐
Oh, my goodness.
我懂  亲爱的
I know, dear.
-他在说什么  -嘘
- What is he talking about? - Shh.
因此  在为未来做准备时
So in preparing for what lies ahead,
我开始意识到  在生命的大部分时间里
I've come to realize that for much of my life,
我一直都错了
I've been mistaken,
我失败了
and I failed.
不仅没能理解人必有一死的事实
I failed, not only to comprehend my mortality,
也没能珍惜这短暂的生命
but I've failed to appreciate it.
结果就是
And as a result,
我没能充分利用我的生命
I've failed to make the most of my life.
维罗妮卡  你是个运动健将
Veronica, you're one hell of a sport.
是个值得尊敬的对手
You are a very worthy adversary.
很骄傲
Proud...
能称你为妻子
to have been able to call you my wife.
因为没有你的生活
Because life without you would've been, uh,
将失色很多
far less rich.
因此  我感谢你
And for that, I thank you.
无论如何
For whatever it's worth...
我爱你
I love you...
深深地爱你
deeply.
我知道
Yeah.
我们已经背弃了
We've turned our backs on the most important duty
我们最重要的职责
that we possess,
那就是过富有经验的生活
to live a life that is rich in experience
这是我们自己选择的
that's of our own independent choosing.
抓住你的存在感  伙计们
Seize your fucking existence, folks.
为何不把死亡当成我们最亲密的伙伴呢
Why don't we make death our closest fucking companion,
这样我们才能有那么一秒钟
so that we can finally have a second,
一毫秒的时间去珍惜
a millisecond to appreciate
我们仅剩的那一点点时间
that little bit of time that we have left.
最最重要的是
And most important of all,
活  就要活得精彩
let us live well,
死  就要死得痛快
so that we may fucking die well,
因为我们从未像现在这样
because we've never been so close to death
离死亡如此之近
than this very moment.
干杯
Cheers.
该死  理查德  那可是水晶杯
Dammit, Richard. Those are crystal.
第五章
是时候了
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry
以这种方式告诉你
that you had to find out like that,
我只是
and I just didn't...
说实话  我不知道该怎么跟你说
I mean, I honestly didn't know how to tell you.
我害怕了
I was scared.
你打算怎么办
What are you gonna do?
我要离开了  甜心
I'm gonna leave, sweetheart.
那正是我打算做的事情
That's exactly what I'm gonna do.
请你  一定试着重新寻找幸福
Please, try and find some happiness.
我正在努力
I'm working on it.
我知道你会的
I know you will.
别了  理查德
Goodbye, Richard.
别了  维罗妮卡
Goodbye, Veronica.
再见
Bye.
奥莉维亚  宝贝  你怎么回家了
Olivia? What are you doing home, baby?
泰勒跟我分手了
Taylor broke up with me.
-怎么回事  -她背着我
- What? - She cheated on me
跟内森·朗宁斯好了
with Nathan Runnings.
朗宁斯教授的儿子
Professor Runnings' kid?
对
Mm-hmm.
听着
Listen. Hey.
来  宝贝  过来
Come on, babe. Come here.
过来
Come here.
别担心  甜心  你会好起来的
Don't worry, sweetheart. You're gonna be fine.
这世界那么多女人
The world's full of women
在寻找爱情
looking for someone to love.
一定会有人配得上你
There's gotta be somebody who deserves you.
-你想喝什么  -无所谓
- What'll you have? - I don't care.
当一个男人分手后
Well, when a man loses a woman,
一般都会喝威士忌解愁
it's, uh, typically whiskey he drinks.
所以说
So,
我觉得
I'm kind of assuming that, um,
拉拉也会想要一样的
a lesbian would do the same.
为了你的未来
Here's to your future.
为锦绣前程
To your bright, bright future.
敬泰勒在地狱里腐烂
To Taylor rotting in hell.
对  敬泰勒在地狱里腐烂吧
And yes, to Taylor rotting in hell.
干杯
Cheers.
我为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
为什么
Why?
因为你就是
Because you possess everything
父亲理想中女儿的样子  甚至更好
that a father could ever want in a daughter, and more.
超乎完美
So much more.
爸
Dad.
嗯  宝贝
Yeah, baby?
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我病了  奥莉维亚
I'm sick, Olivia.
我病了
I'm sick.
会好起来的吗
Are you gonna be okay?
不会
No.
没事的
It's all right.
你会没事的  听到了吗
You're gonna be all right. Do you hear me?
你会很棒的
You're gonna be great.
我会离开一阵子
I'm gonna need to go away for a little bit.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
现在还不知道
I don't really know.
有些事想要搞搞清楚
I just got some things I gotta figure out.
我非常爱你  女儿
Hey, I love you so much, my girl.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
坚持自己的路
You stay on this path of yours.
明白吗
You hear me?
遵从自己的内心  坚持自己的选择
You stay on this path that's yours.
你现在做的就很对  孩子
You're doing it right, kid.
我会非常想念你的
I'm gonna miss you so much.
我爱你
I love you.
吉布斯
Jibbles,
我们上路吧
let's hit the road.
来  吉布斯
Here, Jibbles.
好孩子
Good boy.
一定要让妈妈照顾好你  好吗
You make sure your mom takes good care of you, huh?
我能照顾好自己
I can take care of myself.
我毫不怀疑  孩子
I have no doubt about that, kid.
抱歉  吉布斯
I'm sorry, Jibbles.